Guide to the Richard William Weiland Papers SC0855
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Richard William Weiland papers
1969-2008
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Weiland, Richard William
SC0855
45 Linear Feet (62 boxes)
Collection includes personal correspondence, 1969-2002; materials pertaining to Microsoft, both his career there and the company, 1976-99; his research materials and notebooks on computers, the software industry, investments, and other interests, 1988-2006; papers, yearbooks, notebooks, and other items from his student career, 1971-80 (high school, Oregon State University, Stanford University, and Harvard Business School); materials pertaining to his philanthropic interests; and photographs and other AV materials.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research; materials must be requested at least 48 hours in advance of intended use.
Acquisition Information
This collection was given by Mike Schaefer to Stanford University, Special Collections and University Archives, in 2007 and 2008.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Richard Weiland earned his undergraduate degree in electrical engineering at Stanford in 1976. His first job was with his former high school classmates Bill Gates and Paul Allen at Microsoft, where he managed the completion of the COBOL compiler and helped develop the BASIC interpreter. He left Microsoft in 1988 to pursue full-time philanthropy, where his interests were education; lesbian, gay, bisexual and transgender rights; health and human services; and the environment.
Description of the Collection
The collection includes personal correspondence, 1969-2002; materials pertaining to Microsoft, both his career there and the company, 1976-99; his research materials and notebooks on computers, the software industry, investments, and other interests, 1988-2006; papers, yearbooks, notebooks, and other items from his student career, 1971-80 (high school, Oregon State University, Stanford University, and Harvard Business School); materials pertaining to his philanthropic interests; and photographs and other AV materials.
Computer software industry; Charities; Endowments; Weiland, Richard William; Weiland, Richard William; Microsoft Corporation
- Education, Series 1
  - Elementary School Report Cards (includes 1 class photo) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Lakeside Fall 1981 (alumni magazine?) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Lakeside Course Taught During Winter Quarter 1971 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Information Sciences, Inc. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - "Rick Weiland" name card (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Honors Colloquium, UH111; Intro to Engineering EE101X @ OSU, Fall 1971 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Personal Health, H160 @ OSU, Fall 1971 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Statics, GE211 @ OSU, Fall 1971 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Econ 213: Microeconomics @ OSU, Fall 1971 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Honors Colloquium, UH112 @ OSU, Winter 1972 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Introduction to Logic, Philosophy 203 @ OSU, Winter 1972 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Dynamics, GE212 @ OSU, Winter 1972 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Economics 214: Macroeconomics @ OSU, Winter 1972 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Probability, Math 361 @ OSU, Winter 1972 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Introduction to Digital Design, EE103X @ OSU, Spring 1972 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - General Psychology, Psych200 @ OSU, Spring 1972 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Strength of Materials, GE213 @ OSU, Spring 1972 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Quantitative Business Methods: BA 235 @ OSU, Spring 1972 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Linear Algebra, Math 241 @ OSU, Spring 1972 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - OSU stuff (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Undergraduate (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Religion - in college (Box 2, Folder 4-5)
  - Light and Heat (with lab), Physics 55 and 56 - Stanford, Fall 1972 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Lab Book - Physics 56 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Differential Equations, Math 130 - Stanford, Fall 1972 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Engineering 42 and 41A: Circuits, Electronics, and Electromechanics - Stanford, Fall 1972 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Engineering 41A - Lab Book (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Community Information Systems for Poverty Areas, SWP 128 - Stanford, Fall 1972 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Freshman English, English 1C: Literature and Politics - Stanford, Fall 1972 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - American Government, PS10 - Stanford, Winter 1973 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Circuits I, EE 101 - Stanford, Winter 1973 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Atomic Physics and Lab, Physics 57 and58 - Stanford, Winter 1973 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Lab Book - Physics 57 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Electronics, EE111 - Stanford, Winter 1973 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Electronics, EE111 (handout notes) @ Stanford, Winter 1973 (Box 3, Folder 4-5)
  - Electrical Engineering Lab, EE121 @ Stanford, Winter 1973 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - EE 121 - Stanford Engineering, Winter 1973 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Circuits II, EE102 @ Stanford, Spring 1973 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - American Themes, Spring 1973 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - EE112, Spring 1973 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - 19th and 20th century British History, History 144A @ Stanford, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Manufacturing Technology, ME103 @ Stanford, Spring 1973 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Electronics, EE113 @ Stanford, Fall 1973 (Box 4, Folder 4-5)
  - Elementary Network Theory, EE103 @ Stanford, Fall 1973 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - British Political Systems, PS111A @ Stanford, Fall 1973 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - EE122: Fundamental Transistor Circuits, 1973. AUTH: Michael Frankel (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - "One, Two, Three... Oops! He Doesn't Know How To Count!" - Humbio 6, Nov. 1973. AUTH: Donna Marie Anderson (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - LTC Fall 1973 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Stanford CCC Training - Spring 1973 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Stanford in Britain - CLIVEDEN 1974 (includes photo of Cliveden group and Stanford house dance photo of Nov. 1971) (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - WF 22 - Stanford in Britain (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - History 32 - 20th c. Europe, Winter 1974 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Modern English Composers, Winter 1974 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - English 173A - Shakespeare, Winter 1974 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Winter 1974, Political Sociology (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - English Theatre and Social Change, Spring 1974 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Social Structure of Modern England, Spring 1974 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - ME111 -- Failure Prevention, Spring 1974 (Box 5, Folder 9-10)
  - US Senate - Stanford in Washington (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Elements of Music, Music 21 @ Stanford, Fall 1974 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - EE122 @ Stanford, Autumn 1974 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Laboratory, EE122 @ Stanford, Fall 1974 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Pulses and Timing Circuits, EE211 @ Stanford, Fall 1974 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Solar System Astronomy, AP 101 @ Stanford, Fall 1974 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Symbolic Logic, Philosophy 160A @ Stanford, Fall 1974 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous, Winter 1974 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - ME101: Visual Thinking @ Stanford, Winter 1975 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Course Notes - Electromagnetics EE141 @ Stanford, Winter 1976 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Data Structures Course Notes - CS144A @ Stanford, Winter 1976 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Digital Integrated Circuits, EE313 @ Stanford, Winter 1976 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Computer as a Lab Inst., EE274 @ Stanford, Winter 1976 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - EE274 Lab User's Guide (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Data Structures, CS144A @ Stanford, Winter 1976 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Switch Theory and Logic Design, EE381A @ Stanford, Winter 1976 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Electromagnetics, EE141 @ Stanford, Winter 1976 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Stanford Graduation, June 1976 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Stanford Graduation Pictures (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - SU Diploma (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - "Stanford Daily" Writings (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - "Stanford Daily" Editing (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Stanford Mother's Club of Western Washington directories, 1972-74; graduation photos 1976; and miscellany (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Resurrection: Hoax or History? - Josh McDowell (includes 2 photos of McDowell talking) (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Extracurricular Activities, 1974-5: Stanford in Government, Stanford Surf Club (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - ASSU Senate (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Music/KZSU (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Law School Application Materials (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - MBA Info (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Handbook for MBA Students Entering in 1979 - Harvard (includes one photo) (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Business School (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Harvard Business School, Section A Faculty Directory, 1979-1980 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Harvard Business School MBA Program: Academic Standards and Administrative Policies and Procedures (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Harvard: Production and Operations Management (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Harvard: Marketing (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Harvard MBA: Managerial Economics Midterm, Nov. 14, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Harvard: Finance (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Harvard: Managerial Economics (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Harvard: Organizational Behavior (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Harvard: Control (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Harvard: Management Comm. (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Finance/M.E. (Box 9, Folder 1-2)
  - O.B./CTL/M.C. (Box 9, Folder 3-4)
  - 1979-1980 - 2nd year courses in MBA: Syllabi (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Harvard MBA exams and review packets (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Business Policy I, Spring Semester 1980: Course Syllabus (Box 9, Folder 7-8)
  - Marketing (Box 10, Folder 1-2)
  - Harvard Business School Case Studies 1974-1979 (Box 10, Folder 3-7)
  - Harvard Business School Case Studies 1974-1979 (Box 11, Folder 1-6)
  - Harvard Business School Case Studies 1974-1979 (Box 12, Folder 1-3)
  - 2nd edition, Essentials of Accounting (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Harvard 1980 (Box 12, Folder 5-6)
  - Harvard Business School Annual Report, 1978-9 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Harvard Business School Directory 1979-1980 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Harvard Memorabilia (Box 13, Folder 2-6)
  - Harvard Memorabilia (6 of 11) (Box 14, Folder 1-6)
  - Harvard Business School student activities info. 1979-80 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - "Harbus News" (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Harvard Ephemera (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - New England Maps (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Financial printouts (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Prelaw Handbook: Official Law School Guide, 1973/1974 (Box 54, Folder 1)
  - MIT Bulletin 73/74 (Box 54, Folder 2)
  - 1973-74 Graduate Study in Management: A Guide for Prospective Students (Box 54, Folder 3)
  - Admission Test for Graduate Study in Business (Box 54, Folder 4)
  - Stanford University Bulletin Courses and Degrees 1980-81 (annotated) (Box 54, Folder 5)
  - Approaching Stanford 1972 (Box 54, Folder 6)
  - Engineering in Biology and Medicine, Stanford University 1971-72 (Box 54, Folder 7)
  - Handbook for undergraduate Engineering Programs (SU) 1975-76 (Box 54, Folder 8)
  - Stanford Residence 1973-74 (Box 54, Folder 9)
  - Acceptance letter from Stanford, 1972 (Box 54, Folder 10)
  - Stanford Health Services, People Should Feel Good (Box 54, Folder 11)
  - Pre-professional handbook for law (SU), undated (Box 54, Folder 12)
  - Palo Alto in a Nutshell, a Handbook for College 1973-74; compliments of the Stanford Bookstore (Box 54, Folder 13)
  - MBA [Harvard] preliminary section list, 1979-80 (Box 54, Folder 14)
  - Contact information sheets – Harvard (Box 54, Folder 15)
  - Harvard Business School Student Handbook, 1979 (Box 55, Folder 1)
  - Harvard Business School Prospectus, class of 1981 (Box 55, Folder 2)
  - Harvard Business School Annual Report, 1980 (Box 55, Folder 3)
  - Lakeside Numidian [school yearbook] 1966 (Box 55, Folder 4)
  - Lakeside Numidian [school yearbook] 1967 (Box 55, Folder 5)
  - Lakeside Numidian [school yearbook] 1968 (Box 55, Folder 6)
  - Lakeside Numidian [school yearbook] 1969 (Box 55, Folder 7)
  - Lakeside Numidian [school yearbook] 1970 (Box 55, Folder 8)
  - Lakeside Numidian [school yearbook] 1971 (Box 55, Folder 9)
- Correspondence, Series 2
  - Senator Sam Nunn, US Senate, letter, certificate and photo, 1974, 1979 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Faded apt newsletter with Paul Allen #21 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - (Shirley Douglas) Emails (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Email correspondence, especially CD conversation (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Cards, Notes, Letters from Bob, Rick, and TP (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Queen City Cruise (includes photos, not all of which pertain to the cruise), 1983 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence Misc: Housing (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence Misc (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, 1971-1973 (Box 16)
  - Correspondence, 1973-1976 (Box 17)
  - Correspondence, 1977-1982 (Box 18)
  - Correspondence, 1983-1987, undated (Box 19)
  - Bundled correspondence (Box 20, Folder 1-11)
  - Oversized greeting cards (2), 1978 and undated (Box 63)
- Microsoft, Series 3
  - Poster: Microsoft Product Line 1976-1982
  - Poster: Microsoft Second International Conference on CD ROM March 1987
  - Poster: Mouse Today May 18, 1987; mock-up of newspaper front page with comical stories on computer mice
  - Poster: picture of mainframe computers (decsystem10) set up outdoors, no text, no date
  - Nevada COBOL Manual (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Microsoft - Last Windows Version of Works 7/16/86 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Microsoft C compiler (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Hardware and Cow - Microsoft (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Microsoft - SDM and SLM (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Microsoft - CS and PCODE, Debugger, Tools, Naming (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Word Processing Program - Microsoft Word (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Microsoft File manual (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Microsoft Multiplan: Electronic Worksheet Program (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Microsoft Chart: Complete Business Graphics Program (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Microsoft Basic: Interpreter (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Misc. Re: Microsoft, general technology (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Misc. Re: Microsoft (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Microsoft Career, 1976-87 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Microsoft Financial misc. (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Microsoft Financial misc. (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Windows XP (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Relationship with Microsoft April 1976-April 1979; includes correspondence to and from Bill Gates re: Microsoft (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Microsoft 1981; includes correspondence to and from Bill Gates (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Leaving Microsoft 1987 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Work Notes 1996-1999 (Box 22, Folder 6-7)
  - "People" Magazine, December 1983-January 1984 (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - "Fortune" Magazine, January 1984 (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - "Business Week" April 13, 1987 (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - "Fortune" Magazine, January 5, 1987 (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - April 16, 1984 - "TIME" (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - "Fortune" July 21, 1986 (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - Bill Gates Newspaper Articles (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - Microsoft - Information to Students on Computer Voice Recognition (Box 22, Folder 15)
  - Microsoft Brochures/Catalogs (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Microsoft Consumer Products: Dear Softcard Owner (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Company Meeting 1986-7, Apps Division April 1987 (includes photo) (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Microsoft Employee Newsletter, April 23, 1985 - Apr. 11, 1986 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Microsoft Employee Newsletter, April 18, 1986 - Dec. 19, 1986 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Microsoft Employee Newsletter, Jan. 2, 1987 - July 2, 1987 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Microsoft Employee Newsletter, July 10, 1987 - Dec. 11, 1987 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - CD/ROM, The First International Conference on CD ROM [conference brochure]. Microsoft, Seattle, March 4-7, 1986 (Box 60, Folder 10)
  - Weiland's Microsoft business cards (Box 63)
- Computers other than Microsoft, Series 4
  - PDP11 COBOL reference card (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Model 990 Computer DX10 Operating System - Release 3: COBOL Programmer's Guide (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - CIS COBOL Language Reference Manual (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - CIS COBOL Operating Guide, Version 2 (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - COBOL Operator Guide (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - COBOL Language Manual (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - IBM COBOL Manual (Box 23, Folder 14-15)
  - binder: Software Industry News and Notes, Jul-Dec. 1987 (and earlier) (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - binder: Software Industry News and Notes, 1988 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - binder: Software Industry News and Notes, Jan - June 1989 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - binder: Software Industry News and Notes, Jul-Sep 1989 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - binder: Software Industry News and Notes, Oct - Dec 1989 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - binder: 1988-91 Programming and Analysis News (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - binder: Software Industry News and Notes, Jan - Mar 1990 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - binder: Software Industry News and Notes, Apr - Jun 1990 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - binder: Software Industry News and Notes, Jul - Sep 1990 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - binder: Software Industry News and Notes, Oct - Dec 1990 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - binder: Software Industry News and Notes, Jan - Mar 1991 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - binder: Software Industry News and Notes, Apr - Jun 1991 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - binder: Software Industry News and Notes, Jul - Dec 1991 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - binder: Software Industry News and Notes, Jan - Jun 1993 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - binder: Software Industry News and Notes, Jul - Dec 1993 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - binder: Software Industry News and Notes, Jan - Jun 1994 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - binder: Software Industry News and Notes, Jul - Dec 1994 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - binder: Software Industry News and Notes, Jan - Jun 1995 (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - binder: Software Industry News and Notes, Jul - Dec. 1995 (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - binder: Software Industry News and Notes, Jan - Jun 1996 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - binder: Software Industry News and Notes, Jul - Dec 1996 (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - binder: Software Industry News and Notes, Jan - Jun 1997 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - binder: Software Industry News and Notes, Jul - Dec. 1997 (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - 2200VS COBOL Language Reference Manual (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - An Introduction to CP/M Features and Facilities (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - System-80 Reference Manual (Preliminary) (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - CIS COBOL Language Reference Manual (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - System-Software COBOL (Box 29, Folder 6-7)
  - COBOL Reference Manual for NORD-10 Series Computers (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - PDP-11 COBOL Language Reference Manual (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - Addendum to the decsystem10 COBOL Programmer's Reference Manual (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - PDP-11 COBOL User's Guide and Installation Guide (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - decsystem10 COBOL Programmer's Reference Manual (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - COBOL Brochures (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - decsystem10 - COBOL Utilities Manual (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - CIS COBOL Users Guide (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - COBOL Users Guide: Addendum (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - COBOL Language Specifications: COBOL User's Guide (Box 30, Folder 11)
  - EDITX correspondence and namecards (Box 30, Folder 12)
  - EDITX (Box 30, Folder 13)
  - EDITX Manuals (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - EDITX outline (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - DECSystem-10 letter (EDITX) (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - EDITX May 1972 (Pamphlet creation) (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - EDITX User's Guide (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Abbreviated Guide to EDITX (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Random-Access Processing in EDITX (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - Albuquerque Public Schools & EDITX (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - Cybernetics Corp;, EDITX (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - EDITX Corresp. (Box 31, Folder 10)
  - Information Sciences, Inc - EDITX (Box 31, Folder 11)
  - Commodore 64 - Programmer's Reference Guide (Box 31, Folder 12-13)
  - Logic Simulation Co. (Box 31, Folder 14)
  - Simon, by Logic Simulation Company (Box 31, Folder 15)
  - Simon User's Manual (Box 31, Folder 16)
  - Simon V02 10/8/1970 (Box 31, Folder 17)
  - DecSystem-10 - Applications Software Bulletin (Box 31, Folder 18)
  - DOS II ATARI (Box 31, Folder 19)
  - ATARI850: Interface Module Operator's Manual (Box 31, Folder 20)
  - ATARI 400/800 (Box 31, Folder 21)
  - U. Washington Computer Center, July 1967: General Information Manual (Box 31, Folder 22)
  - Teletype Users' Manual (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - PDP-11 - SORT Reference Manual (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Tops10 SOS Reference Manual (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - COMM-STOR User's Manual (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Tandem Users Guide (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - CSR1 (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - SOS Notes (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - Computers (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - Monitr.opr - July 1969 (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - Microcomputers (Box 32, Folder 9)
  - Ultrabasic-64 (Box 32, Folder 10)
  - Net Change Material Requirements Planning System (Box 32, Folder 11)
  - A Management Guide to Integrated Accounting Systems (Box 32, Folder 12)
  - Continuing Education: Microprocessors Flipchart (Box 32, Folder 13)
  - SIGGRAPH 1982 (Box 32, Folder 14)
  - Informatics Inc. (Box 32, Folder 15)
  - Scientific Systems Services, Inc (Box 32, Folder 16)
  - Computron (Box 32, Folder 17)
  - AMS General Financial System - Summary of Capabilities (Box 32, Folder 18)
  - DataPoint Confidential (Box 32, Folder 19)
  - Open Systems, Inc: Financial Accounting System (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - DataPoint 6600 (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - FLOAT.MAC (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - SYSTEM (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - SOS (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Artificial Intelligence (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - Jerry Feldman - Stanford University Artificial Intelligence Project (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - An Experimental Mobile Automaton - July 1970 (Box 33, Folder 9)
  - Stanford Research Institute (Box 33, Folder 10)
  - Typewriter (Box 33, Folder 11)
  - "Weiland" poster/printout (Box 33, Folder 14)
  - Microsoft Publicity, May 1976 (Box 33, Folder 15)
  - Personal Computing Festival Exhibit Guide (Box 33, Folder 16)
  - NCC 1978 Program Preview (Box 33, Folder 17)
  - UUOCON (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - UUOCON Seq. 2 (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - CLOCK1 (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - EXCELB (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - RTSKD (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - COMCON (Box 34, Folder 6-7)
  - AL10100 (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - National Computing Conference 1976 - Official Exhibit Guide (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - National Computing Conference 1977 - Official Exhibit Guide (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - 1978 National Computer Conference (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - Conference brochures 1987 (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - "TIME" Magazine Feb. 20, 1978 (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - "Scientific American" Sept. 1977 (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - Interactive COBOL (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - AI Article (Box 35, Folder 7)
  - "Fortune" June 10, 1985 - Lotus Development Corporation article (Box 35, Folder 8)
  - Datamation Magazine (Box 35, Folder 9)
  - Reader's Digress (Box 35, Folder 10)
  - "Logical Laws, ...." leaflet (Box 35, Folder 11)
  - Speech Understanding Systems, Final Report of a Study Group, 1973 (Box 56)
  - MOE Microcomputers: Programming Manual August 1975 (Box 56)
  - Introduction to Programming; PDP-8 Family Computers; 1968 (Box 56)
  - A Pocket Guide to Interfacing HP Computers (undated) (Box 56)
  - Logic Handbook: Modules, Hardware, Applications, 1969 (Box 56)
  - A Pocket Guide to the 2100 Computer [HP publication, undated] (Box 56)
  - Small Computer Handbook 1970 Edition (Box 56)
  - Programming Languages PDP-8 Family Computers, 1970 (Box 56)
  - The Elements of Programming Style 1974 (Box 56)
  - PCC’s Reference Book of Personal and Home Computing, edited by Dwight McCabe, 1977 (Box 56)
  - Punchcards related to Lakeside & UW computing (Box 57)
  - Bundled “tape-talk” for EDITX.SHR (Box 57)
  - Spooled tape with programs on it (Box 57)
  - EDITX Reference Guide May 1977 (2 copies) (Box 57)
  - EDITX paper tapes in box (Box 58)
  - Dosket-2000/3000 Floppy Disk Operating System Operation Manual, Version-2 (undated) (Box 58)
  - Gates by Stephen Manes and Paul Andrews (annotated copy) 1993 (Box 58)
  - ’77 NCC [National Computer Conference] Program Roundup (Box 58)
  - NCR IMOS COBOL Student Text 1977 (Box 58)
  - Cobol, by Kenneth P. Seidel 1971 (Box 59)
  - Small Professional Computer – M200 mark series: COBOL-74, 1981 (Box 59)
  - The Apple Macintosh Book by Cary Lu, 1984 (Box 59)
  - COMDEX ’81 Program and Exhibits Guide (Box 59)
  - NCC 82 Exhibit Guide (Box 59)
  - COMDEX/Spring ’87 Program and Exhibits Guide (Box 59)